James Rosenblatt

Mechanical Engineer - Armstrong World Industries

Haddonfield, NJ - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/James-Rosenblatt/4894556336dd7589

WORK EXPERIENCE

Mechanical Engineer

Armstrong World Industries - Lancaster, PA - April 2012 to Present

- Lead engineer on project to implement a new manufacturing line to recycle vinyl tile, working from concept to startup
- o Designed custom processing equipment and specified commercial equipment
- § Custom designed lump breaker, 6 conveyors, 9 motors, 2 bin rotators, chutes and guards
- o Worked with executives, plant representatives, purchasing group and outside vendors to plan and complete project
- §• Executed financial documents and completed purchase orders while managing a \$300k budget
- § Engaged with mechanical and electrical contractors to complete fabrication, installation and startup
- o Recycled content was able to be increased from 3% to 20% due to system efficiency
- Partnered with other engineers on capital plant improvement projects in plants across the country
- Functioned in many kaizen events to help formulate projects and keep manufacturing processes lean

Mechanical Engineer

Halliburton - Houston, TX - November 2009 to March 2012

- Improved safety and manufacturing efficiency through fixture design
- o Devised a fixture for use in 35 places across the entire facility to eliminate lifting strain hazard
- o Helped reduce safety incidents to zero across the shop floor during employment
- Collaborated with design teams to review and release prototype products to production, while practicing GD&T
- Interacted with technicians to solve production issues quickly and maximize company profitability

Mechanical Engineering Co-op

Baker Oil Tools - Houston, TX - September 2007 to March 2008

- Developed a fixture to test material properties used for prototypes
- Assisted in the testing of engineering prototypes with assembly, disassembly and report writing
- Aided other engineers in design process by creating 3D CAD models and shop drawings

Advanced Coatings Manufacturing Engineering Co-op

Pratt and Whitney - East Hartford, CT - September 2006 to March 2007

- Designed and modified tooling and equipment for improved machine function
- o Coater Platter Homing Tool, Patent Number 8,211,234
- · Worked with vendors and machine operators to reduce defects and streamline manufacturing process
- Created and modified operation sheets to ensure proper processing of parts

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science in Mechanical Engineering

Drexel University, College of Engineering - Philadelphia, PA June 2009

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS:

Proven track record of mechanical support ranging from large capital projects to direct manufacturing shop floor assistance. Experienced in a variety of 3D CAD modeling programs and well familiar with design principals, drawing creation and GD&T. Versed in mechanical design of components and equipment. Capable of planning and executing projects while collaborating with plant officials, purchasing groups, corporate employees, outside vendors, and technicians.

COMPUTER PROFICIENCIES

Software, Years Experience, Last Used Consistently, Training Received

Solidworks, 3, 3/2011, 2 Company Provided Training Classes SAP, 4, Current, On the Job AutoCAD, 2, Current, Synergis Professional Class, University Classes Microsoft Office, 10+, Current, University Classes Pro Engineer, 1, 2008, University Classes Helix, 2, 2011, On the Job Microstation, 1, 2006, On the Job